http://www.iiat.org/about-us/privacy-policy

Coronavirus
InfoCentral (Coverage Stuff)
Coronavirus
InfoCentral (Coverage Stuff)
Your privacy on iiat.org
IIAT fully respects the privacy of its members and other visitors to iiat.org. To protect your online privacy, IIAT has implemented the following policy.
Expand all
Collapse all
What Information Does IIAT Collect?
Most of the data IIAT collects is used only to help IIAT  better serve its members. It is our general policy to only collect and store personal information that our members and visitors knowingly and voluntarily provide. If our privacy policies change, we will notify all users by e-mail or a special announcement placed on the Web site.
Data Collected in General
IIAT does not collect any personal information from users browsing our website. Users to the public areas of the IIAT website browse anonymously. Only aggregate data -- such as the number of hits per page or what domain the user came from--are collected. Aggregate data are only used for internal and marketing purposes and do not provide any personally identifying information.
From IIAT Members, Conference Registrants, and Other Customers
To gain access to members-only resources and personalization features on the IIAT website, members and other users may be asked to register and provide some limited information. These data are submitted voluntarily. IIAT asks users to provide their name, member number (for members), organization name, business phone, and e-mail. Similar information may be submitted to IIAT through membership applications, conference or seminar registration, publication orders, subscriptions, and contest registrations.
How Does IIAT Use Data Collected?
IIAT uses information voluntarily submitted by members and other customers in the following ways:
IIAT Member Services and Products
Generally, IIAT will use data collected to improve our own web content; to respond to members’ and visitors’ interests, needs and preferences; and to develop new products and services.
Disclosures to Third Parties
IIAT does not disclose member contact or demographic information to third parties, and all information collected is for member use only, except as otherwise required by law. IIAT does provide IIABA (Independent Insurance Agents of America) with business and personal information on IIAT members. IIAT also give access to limited member data through our Website in the form of search engines. This data is in the form of Name, Address, Phone, Contact, and email for the express purposes of providing the general public a way to access an Independent Insurance Agent who is a member of IIAT and IIABA.
Credit Card Account Information
IIAT does not disclose credit card account information provided by its members and customers. When members and customers choose to pay using their credit cards, IIAT submits the information needed to obtain payment to the appropriate clearinghouse.
How Does IIAT Use Cookies?
Cookies are files that contain information created by a web server that can be stored on a User's hard disk for use either during a particular session ("per-session" cookie) or for future use ("persistent" cookie). IIAT from time to time might use cookies only to facilitate automated activity, store and track passwords, determine appropriate solicitations, and review navigation patterns. Cookies are not used to disseminate significant information about Users over the Internet or to analyze any information that Users have knowingly or unknowingly provided. Users may instruct their Internet browsers to opt out of accepting a "persistent" cookie and rather accept only a "per-session" cookie, but will need to login each time they visit the site to enjoy the full benefits. If the user declines the attachment of any cookie, the user may not have access to the full benefits of the website. Registration enables the site to better determine members' interest areas and provide the most relevant information.
What Privacy Issues Arise With Links To Other Sites?
IIAT's website contains links to other websites. IIAT has no control over and is not responsible for the privacy policies or content of such sites, and the users of the IIAT website “click through” at their own risk.
What Means Of Redress Are Available?
If any User suspects IIAT has handled its personal information in a manner that does not comply with this privacy statement, please contact us by calling (800) 880-7428
Membership Data Privacy Policy
IIAT also gathers information through our relationship with you. Protecting the privacy of your information is a high priority for us. “Non-Public Information” is information received by IIAT and our subsidiaries that identifies you, your business and your individual clients. To protect your information, IIAT has enhanced our privacy policy as outlined below.
As a current member/customer of the Independent Insurance Agents of Texas and Subsidiaries (collectively, “Association”), we would like to take this opportunity both to thank you for your membership/business and to share with you the importance our Association places on protecting the privacy of non-public information we gather from you about you, your business and your individual clients, in accordance with applicable state and federal laws.
The following is the Association’s privacy policy regarding the Non-public information we collect from you through our business relationship with you. Contained in this privacy notice you will find:
An explanation of the types of individual information the Association collects from our members/customers in the ordinary course of business, and the means used to collect such information;
An explanation of how the Association uses and shares the information collected from our members/customers, and
An explanation of how the Association protects individual information received through members/customers.
Expand all
Collapse all
Information We Collect and the Means Used to Collect It
The Association only collects non-public information about individuals from our members/customers that is necessary to provide those services to our members/customers that is usual and customary to professional associations and independent insurance agents. The Association also collects such non-public information for marketing purposes, and provides de-identified, aggregated information to third parties for marketing purposes (that is, information provided to third parties does not contain personally identifying information). The Association collects this information from the following sources:
Non-public information voluntarily provided by individuals on applications or other forms. This information may include, but is not limited to, individual information such as name, address, date of birth, bank account information, and credit card information or member/customer information such as revenues and other financial data points.
Non-public information about individual transactions through our members/customers. This information may include, but is not limited to, claims and payment history. In some instances, this may include an individual’s personal health information.
Non-public information we receive from a consumer-reporting agency. This information may include, but is not limited to, an individual’s driving record.
To collect non-public information from the above-stated sources, the Association may use the following means of communication to gather information: in hard-copy, in-person, by telephone, by facsimile, electronically (such as through email), and on-line (such as through our website). In all
instances, the Association collects this information pursuant to its relationship with our members/customers, and not through a direct commercial relationship with an individual end-consumer.
How We Use and Share Non-Public Information
We use the information described above to service or process the Association offerings and insurance needs of our members/customers; and to better understand and serve the industry as a whole.
We share the information described above with third parties in the following circumstances, as permitted or required by law:
Information that is necessary to service or process the insurance needs of our members/customers, in a manner that is consistent with the usual and customary services provided by independent insurance agents.
Information that is necessary to service or process the Association needs of our clients, in a manner that is consistent with the usual and customary services provided by independent insurance agent associations.
Information that is de-identified, aggregated information for marketing purposes (that is, information provided to third parties does not contain personally identifying information).
Information that is necessary to protect the confidentiality or security of our members’/customers’ records.
Information that is necessary to resolve member/customer disputes or inquiries.
Information that is required by individuals or entities who are assessing our legal compliance.
Information that is required for the Association to comply with a federal or state statute or regulation, governmental inquiry, subpoena response, court order, or other legal requirement.
Information requested by an actuarial or research organization for the purpose of conducting actuarial or research studies.
Information that is necessary to protect against or prevent fraud, unauthorized transactions, legal claims, or other liability.
Under no circumstances will we disclose any personal health information other than as required by law. Under no circumstances will we disclose any account numbers or similar access numbers or codes for marketing purposes.
Our Practices Regarding Information Confidentiality and Security
We maintain reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to guard your information. These safeguards include but are not limited to the following:
We restrict access to non-public information to those employees who need to know that information in order to assist in providing services or products to the customer.
The website employs industry standard security measures to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of information under the Website’s control.Although we have undertaken to create a secure and reliable Website, you should understand that the confidentiality of any communication or material or information provided to or through the Website cannot be guaranteed.Accordingly, you should consider carefully whether to submit sensitive information to the Website.We urge you to take every appropriate precaution to protection your personal identifying information when on-line.
The Association appreciates your business and in order to continue building upon that relationship we believe it is necessary, not only from a legal standpoint, but also as a sound business practice, that our members/customers understand the care our Association uses in handling your information. The Association will continue to monitor the effectiveness of its privacy practices and update you if there are any material changes to those practices.
Terms of Use
Sitemap
Contact Us
Independent Insurance Agents of Texas
1115 San Jacinto, Suite 100
Austin, Texas 78701
800.880.7428
Facebook Twitter LinkedIn
